# **Rolf Gregson**

Contact No: 07519 312 890 Resides: North London Email:rolf.gregson@sky.com

#### **Profile Statement**

An IT professional with over twenty years' experience in infrastructure support and consulting in the banking, government and retail sectors.

Proficient in writing detailed technical reports to support the implementation of new technologies and to justify spend.

Being enthusiastic, meticulous and with excellent interpersonal skills, I work well as an integral part of an agile team and interface well with other teams.

Skills include; AWS, Virtualization, VMware ESXi (all versions), VMware VROPs, Zerto, HP Hardware, 3Par, Pure & EVA Storage, Windows Active Directory, Citrix XenApp, VB script, PowerShell, Linux & Enterprise level backup solutions. Disaster Recovery & High availability, Data Centre Migrations.

I have migrated both Windows and Linux VMware workloads into the AWS platform, designed AWS VPC's and have experience with S3, EC2 & AWS Cloudformation. I have configured Elastic Load balancers, Application Load balancers and have also implemented 'autoscaling' policies,

Past and present certifications include AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate, AWS Certified SysOps Administrator – Associate, AWS Certified Developer – Associate, VMware VCP, MCSE+, Citrix CCA, ITIL v3, Prince 2 Practitioner & Cisco CCNA amongst numerous others.

I am Currently pursing further AWS and Azure certifications.

### **Recent Courses / Training Attended**

- Dell/EMC VMAX All Flash and VMAX3 Business Continuity Management
- Dell/EMC VMAX All Flash and VMAX3 Configuration
- Commvault Core Fundamentals
- Commvault Implementation & Maintenance
- VMware vSphere: Optimize and Scale [5.5]
- RHCSA (Red Hat) Rapid Track.

## **Career History**

#### July 2010 - 2017 ABN AMRO Clearing

- When I joined ABN AMRO there was a minimal VMware presence with no SAN. My remit was to implement/architect a virtualization solution based around VMware and HP hardware.
- I designed and implemented a VMware solution, which started with four ESXi hosts, and an HP EVA SAN. Currently the VMware estate has evolved into an estate of over 50 hosts, a 3PAR SAN and a 'Pure' SAN. About 1200 VM's are under management. This enabled the company to save costs in power, data center footprint and management on running physical servers. I also designed the HP Class Blade infrastructure.
- I also designed and implemented the Virtual Connect connectivity for the HP Blade estate. This solution enabled the 'collapse' of Ethernet and Fiber channel connectivity leading to cost saving for both physical Ethernet and FC Switch ports along with the associated reduced port license costs.
- I evaluated DR solutions for VMware and upon my recommendation implemented 'Zerto Virtual Replication' for VMware. This solution was storage 'agnostic' and enabled the company to have a much more flexible DR solution from a virtualization aspect. It decreased failover times dramatically and made the failover more granular. In addition, it gave the ability to replicated into the 'cloud' should that need arise.
- I migrated virtual machines through several different storage arrays during my time here, i.e. from EVA to 3Par and then to PURE. This involved expanding the SAN from four switches to eight and configuring cross site links with FCIP gateways and DWDM links.
- I managed the SAN including zoning policies and configured monitoring tools to assist in the healthy running of the infrastructure SAN / Fabric.

Sept 2005-Jan 2010

# <u>Kaupthing Singer and Friedlander – Senior Infrastructure Analyst</u>

- Designed and was responsible for the support and upgrade of the VMware ESX infrastructure which included versions 2.5, 3.0x, 3.5 & 4.0. The resulting VMware infrastructure included hosts using HP C class blades and several hundred guest machines.
- Heavily involved in three Data Centre migrations.
- Designed and implemented the backup / DR solution which was comprised
  of two HP EML fiber attached tape libraries; disk based virtual tape libraries, HP Data Protector and two HP SAN EVA 8000 storage arrays all
  connected via a fault tolerant Brocade fiber fabric.
- Project managed / designed the virtualization projects. Analyzed which migration strategies were appropriate.
- Was heavily involved in major Data Centre migrations / implementations at this company
- Designed and implemented several Microsoft based clusters including 4 node SQL and Exchange clusters.
- Part of the team that constructed three tier load balanced architecture for hosting a multi million pound web based internet banking application.
- Designed the management and monitoring of the server hardware in various sites. Hardware which was in use consisted of mainly HP Servers, HP C class blades and a pair of HP EVA disk arrays. Other server hardware included Dell and IBM.
- Documented and trained other members of staff on the technologies I was responsible for.

Nov1996 - Sept 2005

#### Computacenter - Senior Technical Consultant.

- Responded to Bids and Tenders, providing financial and technical analysis and evaluation of alternative technologies and solutions. Produced documented proposals for customer solutions based on specific requirements.
- Worked with vendors to expose customers to new technologies and ideas primarily in the security arena.
- Provided services to many large corporate institutions. Customers included; Lloyds Bank, Barclays, NatWest, Merrill Lynch, British Telecom, Abbey, ING Direct, Debenhams and various Legal & Government bodies such as the Foreign Office and the Greater London Authority, often including user bases of 20,000 or more.
- Led small teams on various customer projects including virtualization projects and datacenter migration projects.
- Implemented high availability/load balanced Nokia VRRP and Nokia IPSO cluster installations. The Nokia IP appliances used included IP120, IP330, IP440, IP530 and IP380's.
- Configured Nokia/Checkpoint firewalls with security policies and VPN's in both distributed and standalone installations for various customers.
- During the dot com boom, provided input to the design and implementation of several new web site/E-commerce network infrastructures for various
- Fulfilled the role of Computacenter's' security coordinator for the Abbey managed service account. This entailed ensuring that Computacenter were compliant with the various Abbey security policies that existed.
- Assisted in Interviewing and recruitment processes.

Jan 1996 - Nov 1996

<u>Sterling Information Technology - Field Engineer / Consultant</u>

1995

May 1995 – Dec Atomstyle Computers – PC Engineer

Prior to 1995, I was employed in a different area entirely. I served a four year mechanical engineering apprenticeship with the British merchant navy.

I then worked for Lucas CAV for a short while before working for the Corporation of London at the Barbican Arts Centre for nine years as a building services technician. I worked with all manner of building infrastructure such as heating, ventilation, air conditioning, refrigeration and gas. I was also CORGI registered at the time.

### Professional Qualifications held in the past

- VMWare vSphere VCP
- Microsoft MSCE NT3.51, NT4.0, 2000 & 2003+Security (Microsoft electives included ISA Server, SQL 2000 Admin', Exchange Admin' & Cluster Server)
- Cisco CCNA
- Prince 2 Practitioner
- ITIL Foundation in IT Service Management
- Nokia Security Administrator (NSA)
- RSA Certified Administrator
- RSA Certified Systems Engineer
- Sun Solaris 7 System Administrator I & II
- Network Associates 'Sniffer' Expert Checkpoint Firewall-1 CCSA & CCSE (V4.1 & NG)
- Citrix Certified Administrator (CCA)
- Compaq ASE, IBM Authorised Servicer / IBM PSS
- Novell CNE 3.12, Intranetware CNE, CNE Netware 5

# **Educational History**

1980-1983 South Shields Marine & Technical College

Higher Diploma in Marine Engineering & Diploma in Marine Engineering

Quintin Kynaston School, London, NW8 1972-1978

Eight 'O' Levels including Maths, English and German

# **Interests**

History, Genealogy, Cycling, Running, Parkrun, DIY, Keep Fit, Guitar